

# **Thomas JEAN-LOUIS**

# **Cloud Engineer**

# **Work Experience**

### Cloud Engineer

### Capgemini - Quidel Ortho I New York (remote)

since sept 2023

Architecture design and Automations for Quidel Ortho in AWS cloud-related projects

- SonarQube migrated to a severless instance, removing EC2 server maintenance and facilitating updates & scalability
- lac pipelines on a .NET monolith web app, that cut lead time by two weeks and installation time by 95%
- Al workflow that extracts data from hundreds of PDFs into an RDS Database for analysis by the business team

Aws Cloud, Azure Devops, CloudFormation, ECS, Fargate, ECR, Textract, Lambda, S3, WAF, Git

#### AR/VR Business Developer - Tech Lead

#### Capgemini I Toulouse, France

feb 2022 - sept 2023

AR/VR Business Development

- Technical and +100k€ financial proposal
- Presentation of AR/VR assets to international client accounts (ex:Airbus, Honda) and institutions (ex: French minister, GIGN)
- Establish technical roadmaps and prioritize new features for a multi-platform remote assistance Capgemini asset

#### AR/VR Technical Leader

- Unity expert and technical referent for AR/VR Bids
- Analysis of partner solutions (ex: PTC, Microsoft) for future collaborations
- Realization of industrial AR/VR experiences

Unity C#, Azure Devops, Azure Cloud, Git

### Virtual Reality Engineer

### Varonia Systems I Tours, France

feb 2019 - feb 2022

Creation (3D scenes, development) of high immersive VR experiences

- Virtual Safari/Escape game played by +15K users in entertainment centers (France, Spain)
- Military simulator tested by the French Army on a tracking area +1000m2
- High-fidelity VR rendering of artworks from the MBA Tours museum

Experiences updated with the last technologies released (hand-tracking, VR streaming)

Unity C#, Blender, Git

# **Personal Projects**

2024

### Serverless multiplayer game platform (Demo available) - 90h

Platform where users can create and join Quake3 games

- Serverless optimized architecture and IaC pipelines to increase agility and optimize costs
- Authentication, user roles and log management to monitor and control demo boundaries
- Multiple independant components for smooth updates

Terraform, Amplify, React, API Gateway, Lambda, Cognito, GitHub Actions, S3, WAF, DynamoDB

### Contact



thomas.jean-louis@outlook.fr



p.thomasjeanlouis.com



<u>linkedin.com/in/thomas-jean-louis-95b454108</u>



France

### **About Me**

Certified Cloud Engineer at Capgemini, I leverage my 6 years of IT experience to advise organizations on cloud strategies, implementing and optimizing cloud solutions.

My expertise focuses on the design and supervision of cloud systems architecture with an emphasis on automation, orchestration and integration.

# Languages

English: fluent

• French: native speaker

### **Education**

# **VR Engineering**

ENSAM Laval - Master

2018 - 2019

### **IT Engineering**

Engineering University, UTC 2013 - 2018

# Certification, Prize

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate, Apr. 2024

IVRC, 2nd prize, Nov. 2019, Japan

## **Skills**

- AWS Cloud Architecture, costing
- lac, CloudFormation, Terraform
- CI/CD, Azure Devops, Github Actions
- Containerization, Docker, ECS
- Scripting, Python, Shell
- Virtualization, EC2, Fargate
- **Security**, IAM, WAF, Certificates
- Al. Textract, Bedrock